Museum Association of Waco records, Inclusive: 1988-2019, undated, Bulk: 1994-2008
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
Museum Association of Waco records
Inclusive: 1988-2019, undated, Bulk: 1994-2008
Baylor University, The Texas Collection http://www.baylor.edu/lib/texas/
586
Museum Association of Waco
7 document boxes
The Museum Association of Waco records contains correspondence, financial and legal documents, minutes, and event information generated by the association, as it supports member organizations through marketing, educating, and financing initiatives.
Administrative Information
Physical Description
General condition: Excellent.
Biography/Profile
The Museum Association of Waco was founded in 1992 to assist member museums in education, marketing, and scholarships and grants. Early efforts to promote Waco-area museums included joint ticketing (one ticket to access multiple local museums), lectures, and workshops. By 2020, the organization had grown to 21 member institutions across the Central Texas area.
Scope and Content
The Museum Association of Waco records contains correspondence, financial and legal documents, including copies of the constitution and bylaws, minutes, and event information generated by the association, as it supports member organizations through marketing, educating, and financing initiatives. Grant information, workshop documents, and membership lists are also included.
Arrangement
The Museum Association of Waco records were arranged in a variety of boxes, binders, and digital media upon donation to The Texas Collection. Original order has been preserved in most folders, except placing materials in chronological order like minutes.
Currently, the Museum Association of Waco records is arranged in five series: I. Correspondence, II. Minutes, III. Membership, IV. Events, and V. Financial and Legal.
Access Restrictions
All requests for copying of materials must be submitted to The Texas Collection in writing. Please use the Request Form for Copying Materials sheet. Unpublished materials authored or otherwise produced by the creator (s) of this collection are in the public domain. There are no restrictions on use. Copyright status for other collection materials is unknown. Transmission or reproduction of materials protected by U.S. Copyright Law (Title 17, U.S.C.) beyond that allowed by fair use requires the written permission of the copyright owners. Works not in the public domain cannot be commercially exploited without permission of the copyright owners. Responsibility for any use rests exclusively with the user.
Acquisition Information
Accession No. 586. Acquired 2019-12-12
Related Resources
Related references
Museum Association of Waco. "Info." Accessed 2020 February 28.
Index Terms
Places
Waco (Tex.).
Subjects
Museums -- Texas -- Waco.; Special events -- Planning.
Genres
Business correspondence.; Financial records.; Financial statements.; Membership lists.; Minutes (Records)
- Correspondence, 1988-2019, undated; 1
  Administrative Information
  Physical Description
  General condition: Excellent.
  Biography/Profile
  This series contains correspondence to and from the presidents of the organization, and occasionally the membership chair. This series is in excellent condition.
  - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, 1992 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence, 2007-2009 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence, 2018 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence, 2018-2019 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Letterhead and Pamphlets, undated (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Minutes, 1991-2019; 2
  This series includes minutes from the association. This series is in excellent condition.
  - Minutes, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 1992 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 1993 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 1994 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Minutes, 1995 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 1997 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 1998 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 1998 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 1999 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2000 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2001 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2002 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2002 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2003 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2004 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2005 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2005 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2006 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2006 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2007 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2007 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 2008 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Minutes, 2009 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Minutes (1 of 2), 2010 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Minutes (2 of 2), 2010 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Minutes, 2011 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Minutes, 2012 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Minutes, 2013 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Minutes, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Minutes, 2015 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Minutes, 2016 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Minutes, 2017 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Minutes, 2018 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Minutes, 2019 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Membership, 1991-2014; 3
  This series includes membership materials, including membership lists and demographic studies of visitors to member institutions. This series is in excellent condition.
  - Membership Lists, 1991-1992 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Membership Lists, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Membership Lists, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Membership Lists, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Membership Lists, 1999-2000 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Membership Lists, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Membership Lists, 2002 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Membership Lists, 2003 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Membership Lists, 2008 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Membership Lists, 2014 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - Visitor Demographics Study (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - Visitor Demographics Study (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Events, 1993-2002; 4
  This series includes events that the Museum Association of Waco hosted or promoted, including joint ticketing data, workshops, and Celebrate Waco. The joint ticketing data appears to have been from a program that allowed visitors to purchase one ticket on specified days that would allow entry to multiple member museums across Waco. This series is in excellent condition.
  - Workshop, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Workshop, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Workshop, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Joint Meeting, “Visitor Psychology”, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Joint Quarterly Workshop, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Heritage Communications Training, 1994-1996 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Waco Funfare Joint Ticketing (1 of 2), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Waco Funfare Joint Ticketing (2 of 2), 1993 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Waco Funfare Joint Ticketing (1 of 2), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Waco Funfare Joint Ticketing (2 of 2), 1994 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Waco Funfare Joint Ticketing (1 of 2), 1995 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Waco Funfare Joint Ticketing (2 of 2), 1995 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Waco Funfare Joint Ticketing (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Waco Funfare Joint Ticketing (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Celebrate Waco (1 of 5), 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Celebrate Waco (2 of 5), 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Celebrate Waco (3 of 5), 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Celebrate Waco (4 of 5), 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Celebrate Waco (5 of 5), 1999-2000 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Celebrate Waco, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Celebrate Waco, 2002 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Museum Marketplace, 2015 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Museum Marketplace, 2016 (Box 6, Folder 9)
- Financial and Legal, 1992-2016; 5
  This series includes financial and legal materials, including financial tracking sheets, copies of the constitution and bylaws through time, and grant paperwork. This series is in excellent condition.
  - Balance Sheets, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Balance Sheets, 1993 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Balance Sheets, 1994 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Balance Sheets, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Balance Sheets, 1996 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Balance Sheets, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Refocus Proposals (1 of 2), 1996 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Refocus Proposals (2 of 2), 1996 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Museum Association of Waco and Museum Studies Student Association Agreement, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Waco Foundation Grant, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Cooper Foundation Grant, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Summerlee Foundation Grant, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Co-Ticket Operating Procedures Agreement, Phase 3, 1995 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Co-Ticket Operation Procedures Agreement, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Officer Job Duties, 2010 (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1992 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1994-1995 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 2005, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Constitution and Bylaws, 2010, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Bylaws, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Bylaws, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Bylaws, 2007 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Bylaws, 2014 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Bylaws, 2016 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Non-Profit Status, 1993 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Non-Profit Status, 1996 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Non-Profit Status, 2006 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Non-Profit Status, 2013 (Box 7, Folder 22)